Guide to the Abraham Anson papers, 1939-2005
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
- Series 3:: Publications, 1943-2005 (Boxes 13-31)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 322-478, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 479-626, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 628-732, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 733-874, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 875-1019, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 1020-1093, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 1094-1232, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 1233-1378, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 1379-1480, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 1481-1552, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "Chronological History of the American Society For Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing". Draft. Pages 1553-1636, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Daily Itinerary from the Fourth International Symposium on Computer-Assisted Cartography, November 5, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - National Geographic Educational Posters: Earth's Moon and Indians of North America, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - 949th Engineer Topographic Company Pamphlet, January 1943 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Article from Second Army Sentinel, May 10, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Aerial Photographs and "From Plane Table Topography to Photogrammetry" By Abraham Anson, circa 1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Potomac Region Annual Report 1998, February 12, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Comparison Supplement to "Memo-to-File Test and Evaluation of the Kelsh Plotter KPP-3", June 14, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "Graphical Mapping with Convergent Photography" By Abraham Anson, April 18, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Annual Indexes to Photogrammetric Engineering and Remote Sensing, 1979-1981 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Historical Highlights of Photogrammetry In The U.S., 1913-1984 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clipping of Obituary for Harold Teddy Rib, June 2, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clipping About Belvoir Awards, January 28, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - "Underwater Photography" By Gomer T. McNeil, June 1972 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - "The MLA Style Sheet" Compiled by William Riley Parker, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - American Society of Photogrammetry Color Committee Member List, March 1970 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Subject Index, circa 1950 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Annual Index to Photogrammetric Engineering and Remote Sensing, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - "Automatic Mapping of Strip Mine Operations from Spacecraft Data" Prepared by Bendix Aerospace Systems Division, September 3, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Letter from The Department of the Interior, December 1974 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - "Preliminary Report on a Multispectral Experiment" Prepared by Abraham Anson, February 18, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - "Color Aerial Photography"by Carl H. Strandberg, circa 1970 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Agard Publications on Aerial Photography, December 1966-June 1971 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Aerial Photography Conference Roster, May 1971 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - List of Mapping Cameras Used for Aerial Photography, circa 1970 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Geographic Information Systems Division Personnel Roster, December 1972 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - "Automatic Mosaicking System" by Abraham Anson, March 1962 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with The Department of the Interior, November 1946-October 1951 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - "Color Photography from the Film Manufacturer's Standpoint" by Raife G. Tarkington, January 1955 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Notes for Photogrammetry Course at University of Illinois, April 1969 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Army Engineer Topographic Laboratories Information Kit, June 1980 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - "A Feasibility Study of Portable Spectrophotometer Systems" by K.D. Robertson, July 1965 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Final Technical Report for the Institute of Optics at The University of Rochester, March 15, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - "Geometric Considerations for an Automated Mapping Satellite System", March 13, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Aerial Photographs and Correspondence with the American Society of Photogrammetry, 1956-1969 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Name and Subject Index, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Photogrammetric Engineering and Remote Sensing Publication List, December 1982 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - "Automatic Exposure Control for Aerial Cameras" by H.K. Meier, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - "Experience in the Application of Spectrozonal Aerial Photographs for Topographic Interpretation" by V. Zh. Shoyvanov, August 31, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - "Materials Research and Standards", February 1968 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - United States Department of the Interior "Topographic Division Bulletin" Volume 1, March 1951 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "Effects of Supersonic and Hypersonic Aircraft Speed Upon Aerial Photography", August 1959 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "Remote Sensing (the historical and hysterical past)" by J. Robert Quick, August 1976 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - The Potomac Region Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Newsletters, Fall 1997 and Spring 1998 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - "Effects of Supersonic and Hypersonic Aircraft Speed Upon Aerial Photography", 1960 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Effects of Supersonic and Hypersonic Aircraft Speed Upon Aerial Photography", 1960 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Professional Surveyor Magazine: "Bringing the Gulf Coast Back to Life", November 2005 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Imaging Notes" Volume 20, Fall 2005 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Brochures for Geographic Information Systems, 1987-1997 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Report on Aerial Photography and Automatic Mosiackers by Abraham Anson, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - "History of The American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing" Manuscript, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" Manuscript by Abraham Anson, Chapters 3, 4, and 5., 1973 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" Manuscript by Abraham Anson, Chapters 10 and 12., 1973 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" Manuscript by Abraham Anson, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Advisory Commission on Mapping, Surveying, and Land Information Systems"- Recommended Draft, December 3, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" Draft with Corrections by Abraham Anson, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "Applications of Color and Multispectral Techniques" by Abraham Anson, April 1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "Aerial Photography and Photogrammetry" Article by Abraham Anson, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "Virginia Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "Puerto Rico and The Virgin Islands Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - "Maine Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "Stereo Acuity Study by the University of Rochester" Draft, November 17, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "Color-A New Dimension in Photogrammetry" Article by John T. Smith, Jr., November 1963 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "Color Applications to Military Geographic Intelligence" by Abraham Anson, circa 1970 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - "New Hampshire and Vermont Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Massachusetts, Rhode Island, and Connecticut Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "Maryland, Delaware, and District of Columbia Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "Florida Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "Washington Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "South Carolina Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "Kentucky Index to Topographic and Other Map Coverage", 1990 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Presentation Notes on Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - The National Map: Topographic Maps for the 21st Century, February 2002 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Topographic Map Symbols, November 1966 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "Autobiography of Lieutenant Colonel Abraham Anson" Manuscript and List of Publications by Abraham Anson, circa 1980 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Engineering Research and Development Laboratories Yearbook, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Department of Defense Image Interpretation Handbook, Volume 1, December 1968 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Status of Aerial Color Photography in Government Agencies, May 1968 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Photogrammetry Comparative Photointerpretation and Photographs (1 of 2), circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - American Society of Photogrammetry Comparative Photointerpretation and Photographs (2 of 2), circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Growth of the American Society of Photogrammetry, Chapter 5., circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Growth of the American Society of Photogrammetry, Chapter 6., circa 1960 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - The Potomac Region Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Newsletters and Budget, February 1966-January 1991 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - "Photogrammetry for Non-Topographic Military Applications" by Abraham Anson, September 1971 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Preface by Robert H. Lyddan, June 1973 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "Photo Mosaics from Space" Catalog, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Technical Report on 17-TR Prototype Automatic Mosaicking System, November 14, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "Clark's 103rd Meridian" by Fred Roeder, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "Several Unclassified Research Projects at the USAGIMRADA from 1957-1973", 1975 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Stereo Photos Amplify Lunar Soil Info" Article, August 1962 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - "Photographic Interpretation From Space" by Abraham Anson. Chapter 10., circa 1970 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - "Supplement to Preliminary Report on a Multispectral Experiment" By Abraham Anson, June 3, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Army Memorandum About Visual Errors In Anaglyphic Plotting, April 13, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Illustrations and Notes on Photogrammetry and Stereoplotting Equipment, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Illustrations and Notes on Aerial Photography, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - The Potomac Region of The American Society of Photogrammetry Rosters, 1952-1991 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Mapping in Puerto Rico" by J.J. McKeon and Abraham Anson, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Manual Of Color Aerial Photography, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - U.S. Department of the Interior "Steps to the Moon" Booklet, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Brochure About Western Honshu, Japan, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Patent Specification 922923 for Colour Projectors and Cameras, April 17, 1959 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - "A New Approach To Meteorite Studies" Article (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - American Society for Testing and Materials 70th Annual Meeting Pamphlet, June 1967 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing 60th Anniversary Awards Luncheon Program, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Pocket Engineering Booklet, 1946-1949 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "Aerial Photography and Photogrammetry in the Coast and Geodetic Survery" by Lawrence W. Swanson, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - "Mapping the Appalachians" by Abraham Anson. Chapter 1., 1998 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - "AMS Life" Newsletter, October 2004 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Topographic Map Symbols, August 1993 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Description of Cartographer Duties, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Magazine Article on Shock Waves, circa 1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Order Form for ASP Manual of Remote Sensing, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Agenda for Great Lakes Survey Briefing, April 3, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Von Gruber's "Circling Effect" Memorandum, January 21, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - "Physiology of the Eye" by Francis Heed Adler, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - "A Proposed Investigation of the Purkinje Effect" by Abraham Anson, circa 1965 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Photogrammetry Reference Material, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Graph from Photogrammetry Publication, circa 1960 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Table 1 from Van Gruber's "Circling Marks", circa 1970 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - "An Evaluation of Photo Display Modes for Extraction Of Intelligence Information" by Dr. Abraham H. Birnbaum, October 1962 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Memorandum About "Classical Figures of Helmholtz", October 19, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - American Society of Magazine Photographer's Picture Annual, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Photography Annual, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Photography Annual, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Photography Annual, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Photography Annual, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Arts Magazine, August 1956 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - "Moscow" Book, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, January 1956 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, February 1956 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, May 1956 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, June 1956 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, July 1956 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, August 1956 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, September 1956 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, October 1956 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, November 1956 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, December 1956 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Popular Photography Magazine, August 1965 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" Manuscript and Notes by Abraham Anson, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - "Topographic Mapping with Plane Tables and Alidade in the 1940's" by Abraham Anson, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing Potomac Region Board Meeting Notes, June 20, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Drafts, Photographs, and Toporaphic Maps, circa 1950 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - GeoTech 2000 Workshop #3 Program, October 16, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Earthdata Booklets on Photogrammetry, May 1999 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "A History of Military Mapping Camera Development" by R.G. Livingston, May 1, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "Multisensor Imagery Collection" Prepared for the Earth Resources Survey Program, December 1965 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Drafts for Review, 8x11 inch Black and White Photographs, and Notes About Automatic Mosaicking Systems, 1943, 1960-1966 (Box 31, Folder 3)